

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

**Lead Technology Consultant** with around 12.3 years of competitive experience specializing in Frontend and Backend development with the latest technologies like Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, Breeze JS, Node JS, C#, WEB API, ASP.NET MAVC, Angular Material, Bootstrap, SCSS, etc.

## **HIGHLIGHTS**

- C#, JavaScript, Typescript,
- .NET, MVC, ASP.NET CORE
- Angular, ReactJS, Node JS
- SQL, Oracle, MongoDB
- MS Azure, GIT

- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused

Linked-In: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/rabbani4007/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/rabbani4007/</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/rabbani4007/

# **EXPERIENCE -**

06/2022 to till date	Tech Lead	R Systems - Noida
03/2020 to 06/2022	Lead Consultant	ITC Infotech - Gurugram
06/2014 to 03/2020	Module Lead	Mercer Consulting - Gurugram
02/2012 to 06/2014	Software Engineer	Chetu Inc. – Noida
01/2010 to 02/2012	Software Engineer	Radix Info Solution – New Delhi

# Projects -

Project Name: GuestRev ,GroupRev,RevIntel

Role: Lead Developer

Team Size: 8

Environment: C#, C++ , JavaScript, Python ,R, MS SQL, ASP.NET Core REST-full APIs and EF CORE ,

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, development, bug fixing, unit testing. Worked to implement

new functionality and module from client to server.

Description: GuestRev provides a platform to manage Short Term Disability, Workers' Compensation, Workplace

Accommodation and Company Leave Plans for our clients. This platform acts as an Absence Management

system that will track and obtain case information across all clients.

**Project Name: AbsenceConnect** 

Role: Lead Developer

Team Size: 8

Environment: C#, Angular, Typescript, Node JS, MS SQL, ASP.NET Core REST-full APIs and EF CORE, SOA, Micro Services,

Rabbit MQ, AKS, Docker

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, development, bug fixing, unit testing. Worked to implement

new functionality and module from client to server.

Description: AbsenceConnect provides a platform to manage Short Term Disability, Workers' Compensation, Workplace

Accommodation and Company Leave Plans for our clients. This platform acts as an Absence Management

system that will track and obtain case information across all clients.

Project Name: SYS FLOW

Role: Lead Developer

Team Size: 2

Environment: Angular, Typescript, Breeze JS Node JS, MS SQL, AG-GRID, ASP.NET Core REST-full APIs and EF CORE

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, development, bug fixing, unit testing. Worked to implement

new functionality and module from client to server.

Description: SysFlow is OG&C Project Engineering's new hydraulic tool that will replace legacy PPS to construct hydraulic

models of systems in process plants that require steady-state flow analysis. It will consume external process simulation data for mass & energy streams and apply rule-based pipe sizing to the flow results for all pertinent flow cases in order to compute the optimal pipe sizes. It will manage the process and physical design basis for all piping, inline flow instrumentation, and hydraulic equipment in the context of the project Piping and

Instrument (P&ID) schematics and Piping Material.

Project Name: Team Works, TW API and WITS

Role: Lead Developer

Team Size: 4

Environment: C#, ASP.NET WEB API, WIN APPLICATION, MS SQL, Linq

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, development, bug fixing, unit testing. Worked on Restful service

implementation with high performance in TW API and Fixes issues/added new functionality in TW and WITS.

Description: TEAMWorks is Bechtel's standard software for Tracking Equipment and Material at project sites. TEAMWorks

development is sponsored by the Construction functional group and is designed specifically for enhancing the Construction and Startup work processes. TEAMWorks also enables users to track and report work progress at

job sites. They have now been integrated in TEAMWorks to ensure seamless end-to-end automation of

monitoring, tracking and reporting activities at job sites. WITS is a specialized part of TW's welding and related

group.

**Project Name: Mercer Online Classified** 

Role: Module Lead

Team Size: 4

Environment: Angular, Node JS, Express, Mongo DB, JWT

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, development, bug fixing, unit testing

Description: This application is built to provide the online product marketplace where user can upload their product for re

sale. User can view and browse the product that is meant to sale. User can send an interest, message to the

seller, can shortlist the product. Product can be approved by supervisor /admin.

**Project Name: Process Flow/Client Profile** 

Role: Module Lead

Team Size: 6

Environment: C#, MVC 4, Web API, Angular JS, Lodash , Bootstrap, LINQ, EF etc.

Responsibilities: Involved in requirement gathering, analyzing, bug Fixing, development, unit testing and integration testing

Description: This application is built to automate the client profile details, process and task scheduling with multiple

options for Large Markets and MM365 clients in US. The application loads the client related data from Unity servers for multiple clients like consulting, OE etc. There are more than 50 reports that have filtration,

pagination, sorting and custom exporting functionality. There are more than 6 watchers that load the client

data on different frequency configured by CRON job.

Project Name: AFBO / Outgoing File Management/Cordys/EWM

Role: Module Lead

Team Size: 4

Environment: VS2010, ASP.NET 4.0, C#, SQLServer2008, Oracle, IBATIS, GEO Framework, WCF

Responsibilities: Involved in Requirement Gathering, Analyzing, Bug Fixing, Coding, Unit testing and Integration Testing

Description: Application Foundation Back Office (AFBO) is built to set the metadata for Carrier and Trustee file that

includes functionality e.g., frequency, GPG encryption, files transmission, job details and notification setups for a particular vendor file and for a selected client. That file will be used by the Cordys(a BPM tool from Open Text) to perform multiple task in workflows using OGFM windows service. OGFM is a WCF service used to kick

off the Cordys workflow, process the file, extraction, encryption, transmission and sending notification.

Project Name: Cordys Security Sync/Mercer MarketPlace/Outbound WorkFlowRequest

Role: Module Lead

Team Size: 4

Environment: C#, MVC 4, Web API, Knockout JS, Lodash , Bootstrap, LINQ, EF, IBATIS etc..

Responsibilities: Involved in Requirement Gathering, Analyzing, Bug Fixing Coding, Unit testing and Integration Testing

Description: Cordys Security Sync is built to synchronize the user roles, client details, task details to Cordys and generate

the reports with logs. It's a console based application that uses two DB and Cordys web service to perform

transition on daily basis. I worked to enhance the application performance and fixed the bugs.

Mercer marketplace and OFWR are web based application with window services. Those applications are built

to generate the report and configuration that was later used by Cordys in workflow.

Project Name: EZTransport / WMATA/ PaywareConnect/ SeniorStat /GlobalDirect (MJM Innovations Transport)

Role: Software Engineer

Team Size: 5

Environment: VS2012, MVC 4.0, C#, SQL Server 2008, WCF, JQuery, TFS 2012, SSRS

Responsibilities: Involved in Requirement Gathering, Analyzing, Coding, Unit testing and Integration Testing

Description: The project belongs to the MJM Innovations which facilitate the admin to configure and manage the

transportations related the rider. The application contains Contact Manager and Account Manager Module.

The Contact Manager module is used to configure/handle the Participant/Rider activities like category, issue; card lost, search rider/public contact and attached workflow actions etc. The account manager module is used to upload/filter/process the invoice/provider excel sheet and configure various activities like pick, drop and invoice details. The project also contains the SSRS Report which is based on the participant/activity and transaction related information.

Project Name: ChibahSys (Online Game Portal)

Role: Team Member

Team Size: 4

Environment: VS2010, C#, SQL Server 2008, WCF, LINQ, HTML5, ASP.NET, MVC4, JQuery

Responsibilities: Involved in Requirement Gathering, Analyzing, Coding, Unit testing and Integration Testing

Description: The project was based on the online reel and slot game portal that has HTML5 based layout from our side.

The game is also scalable to mobile devices like IOs, Android and Window phone. The game is the part of existing Island Luck portal and played in real time and real money with the registered user. Game portal and the admin module communicates with the WCF Restful service for the action in a secure manner. The game portal in made in asp.net MVC 4 and admin in the normal asp.net platform with LINQ to access the database objects. The application contains the payment integration form the third party.

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

Got 1 times star of the month award in Mercer for performance upgrade in application code base.

Got 2 times team of the quarter award in Mercer for good teamwork in the project.

#### **EDUCATION**

2012 M.Sc. Information Technology

Sikkim Manipal University — New Delhi, Delhi, India

2010 GNIIT (3 years' diploma in Software Engineering)

NIIT — New Delhi, Delhi, India

2009 B.Sc. (Honors in Math)

**Vinoba Bhave University** — Hazaribagh, Jharkhand, India

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: Yusuf Ansari

Sex: MaleNationality: IndianMarital Status: Married

### **SKILLS**

- Web development using Typescript, Angular and Web API
- Strong experience in MVC5, C#, Web Services and WCF
- Production server handling and management
- Web deployment and IIS configuration handling
- Using Agile model for application development
- People management
- High level of experience in debugging skills.
- Good knowledge of OS and IIS concepts

(MD GHULAM RABBANI)